PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
Hello. Hold on for just a second, please. Welcome to "Rendering."
你们好 请先稍等一会儿 欢迎来到“渲染”
I'm Christophe Hery and I'm a researcher at Pixar.
我是 Christophe Hery 皮克斯的研究员
Rendering is the last phase of the pipline and film production
渲染是电影制作和流水线的最后一个阶段
that takes our movies from this to this.
渲染的目的是使我们的电影从这样 变成这样
Rendering is where the world we've created in the virtual three-dimensional space
渲染是要把我们在计算机里的三维虚拟空间中
of the computer is finally realized as a series of perfectly rendered
所创造的世界，最终通过一系列
two-dimensional images that play one after another
一个接一个播放的完美呈现的二维图像
for 96 minutes and become our movie.
成为我们时长96分钟的电影
Rendering is an incredibly time-consuming process,
渲染是一个极为耗费时间的过程
all focused on answering one simple question:
所有答案的焦点都指向一个问题
"What color is this pixel – and then this pixel –
这个像素的颜色是什么？还有这个像素的？
and then this pixel and this pixel?"
还有这个像素的？还有这个像素的？
Seems simple enough.
看似很简单
I mean, the balloon is blue, so the pixel will be blue, right?
我的意思是 气球是蓝色的 然而这个像素就是蓝色 是吗？
Well not exactly.
不全然对
A pixel is a tiny portion of the final image.
一个像素是一幅图像极小的一部分
It acts like a little window into the virtual 3D world.
它的作用就像一个进入三维世界的窗口.
To understand what color it should be,
要了解它是什么颜色
we have to figure out what part of the picture
我们就必须弄清
we see through that window.
它是我们透过窗口看到的画面的哪一部分
We translate this question, "What color is this pixel?", into math.
我们把“这个像素是什么颜色的？”转换为一个数学问题
This equation is called the "rendering equation."
这个方程叫“渲染方程”
It's a mathematical description of how light bounces around in the environment.
这是一个关于光如何在环境中四处反射的数学描述
I know we said "color." And this equation is about light.
我知道我们在说“颜色” 而这个方程是关于光的
But there's a good reason for that.
但这是一个很好的推理
Color is light – just light +of different wavelengths.
颜色其实就是光 不同波长的光
So when we ask the question, "What color is this pixel?",
所以当我们问“这个像素是什么颜色的？”的时候
we're really asking "What light is coming through this pixel towards the camera?"
我们真正在问的其实是“是什么光穿过了这个像素到达摄像机？”
The solution to the equation will be the answer to our question.
方程的答案能够回答我们的问题
"This pixel is – purple?" [Asks in an unsure way.]
“这个像素是 紫色的？” （不确定的语气）
To render a movie like "Up," we have to ask this question:
渲染一部像《飞屋环游记》这样的电影 我们必须回答这个问题
"What color is this pixel?" billions and billions of times.
“这个像素是什么颜色的”数十亿次
But just like every part of this process, each little calculation isn't hard to do.
但就像渲染这个过程的每一部分 每个小小的计算都不难做到
It's the layer upon layer of calculation that makes it complex,
是一层又一层的计算使得它变得复杂
but also makes it possible to bring something this beautiful to the screen. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
但也使它有可能为屏幕带来像这样如此美丽的东西 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox